## **Mohammed-Yousuf Hamid**

Oxford, United Kingdom

Email: mohammedyousufhamid@gmail.com
GitHub LinkedIn

## **Personal Profile**

I am a motivated, enthusiastic and goal-oriented individual, always striving to achieve the highest standard possible. I have demonstrated the ability to provide a high level of customer service and have experience in handling customer enquiries both face-to-face and via telephone. My commitment and willingness to learn is shown in my self-study of programming languages to widen my knowledge and skill set.

# **Key Skills and Achievements**

- Leadership Award in IT Gosford Hill School.
- Creating web applications using HTML, CSS and JavaScript.
- Knowledge of CSS Pre-processors and frameworks such as Sass, Tailwind and Bootstrap.
- Confident in using Version Control Systems such as Git.
- Capable of turning designs into working code with consideration to responsive design, performance and accessibility.
- Comfortable with using the Terminal and Browser Developer Tools.

# **Education & Qualifications**

City of Oxford College (Blackbird Leys Campus) - BTEC Level 3 National Extended Diploma September 2019 - July 2021

- Principles of Computer Science
- Fundamentals of Computer Systems
- Planning and Management of Computer Projects
- Software Design and Development
- IT Systems Security and Encryption
- Website Development
- Object-Oriented Programming
- Computer Networking

# Gosford School – 10 GCSEs May 2019

- IT Distinction
- Science 7/6
- Math 6
- English 6
- Business 5
- Geography 5
- Resistant Materials 5
- Religion Philosophy and Ethics 5

#### Online Courses - Udemy, Codecademy and Frontend Masters

- Modern HTML & CSS from the Beginning (Including Sass)
- Modern JavaScript from the Beginning
- Essentials in JavaScript ES6
- From Fundamentals to Functional JS v2
- Learn Responsive Design

# **Employment History**

## **Bird Marketing - Web Developer Apprentice**

#### July 2021 - Present

Key Responsibilities:

- Developing, editing and maintaining WordPress websites.
- Building framework systems on Laravel.
- Fixing and debugging existing websites.
- Promptly responding to incoming tickets.
- Setting up and managing emails and domains.

#### WHSmith - Sales Assistant June 2019 - July 2021

Key Responsibilities:

- Deliver a friendly service, smiling, greeting and making eye contact with every customer.
- Operate tills efficiently to provide a positive customer experience.
- Complete stock replenishment, ensuring all areas of the store remain tidy.
- Effectively work as a team member, supporting colleagues in all tasks
- Meet high standards of display and visual merchandising to ensure the store is well presented.
- Demonstrate good product knowledge to customers on key promotions and offers.

#### Interests

In my spare time I enjoy coding. I have learnt various computer languages such as: HTML, CSS, Sass and JavaScript, through self-study and exercise my learning through projects ranging from applications to small components. I also enjoy table tennis and have played for the school team to compete regionally against other schools. Additionally, I channel my creativity by drawing characters from TV series and solving the Rubik's cube.

## **References Available on Request**